Hello English learners, welcome back to another great podcast here at EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到 EnglishPod 的另一期精彩播客。
My name is Marco.
我是 Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是 Erika。
And today we're going to be talking about one of our favorite topics as always.
今天我们要聊一个我们一直最喜欢的话题。
Food.
食物。
We're going to be at a restaurant.
我们要去一家餐厅。
And, you know, one of the most difficult or embarrassing things to deal with at a restaurant
你知道，在餐厅里最尴尬或最难处理的事情之一
is what to say when you don't like the food or when it's bad quality food.
就是当你不喜欢食物或者食物质量差时该说什么。
Right.
没错。
So maybe we have to complain about the food or maybe even the service, right?
所以也许我们得抱怨食物，甚至服务，对吧？
That's right.
对。
And in this lesson, we're going to be learning some really wonderful words and phrases that
在这节课里，我们将学习一些非常棒的单词和短语，
you can use when you need to complain about the food or the service in a restaurant.
当你需要在餐厅抱怨食物或服务时可以使用。
Okay.
好的。
So before we listen to what happens in this restaurant with this food, let's take a look
所以在听这家餐厅里关于食物的故事之前，我们先快速看一下
very quickly at vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
Okay.
好的。
We're only going to do one word today.
今天我们只讲一个词。
And this you'll hear in the dialogue.
这个词你会在对话中听到。
An establishment.
一家场所。
Establishment.
场所。
This kind of establishment.
这种场所。
Okay.
好的。
So when I say an establishment, that's a noun.
所以当我说“场所”时，它是一个名词。
What is an establishment?
什么是场所？
It's basically a fancy word for a business or a restaurant in this case.
基本上就是“企业”或“餐厅”的正式说法，这里指餐厅。
In this case, it's a restaurant.
这里指的是餐厅。
Yeah.
是的。
But in general, you can say it's a business.
但一般来说，你可以说它是一个企业。
So you have a very fine establishment.
所以你有一家很高级的场所。
That's right.
没错。
So an establishment, a type of business, a place of business, really.
所以场所，一种企业，一个经营场所，真的。
Very good.
很好。
All right.
好的。
So now it's time for us to listen to our dialogue.
现在是时候听我们的对话了。
We're going to find out what's going on here.
我们要看看这里发生了什么。
Apparently, there is a very angry customer and we're going to find out why.
显然，有一个非常生气的顾客，我们要找出原因。
Excuse me, waiter.
打扰一下，服务员。
Yes, sir.
是的，先生。
What can I do for you?
我能为您做什么？
I've been sitting here for the past 20 minutes and no one has offered me a glass of water,
我在这里坐了20分钟，没人给我倒杯水，
brought any bread to the table, and our appetizers haven't been served yet.
没拿面包上桌，我们的开胃菜也没上。
You know, in this kind of establishment, I'd expect much better service.
你知道，在这种场所，我期待更好的服务。
I'm sorry, sir.
对不起，先生。
I'll check on your order right away.
我马上去查您的订单。
Relax, honey.
放松点，亲爱的。
The place is busy tonight and I've heard the food is amazing.
今晚这里很忙，我听说食物很棒。
Anyway.
不管怎样。
Here you are, sir.
给您，先生。
The foie gras for the lady and a mushroom soup for you.
鹅肝给女士，蘑菇汤给您。
Waiter!
服务员！
I ordered a cream of mushroom soup with asparagus.
我点的是芦笋奶油蘑菇汤。
The soup is obviously too runny and it's over seasoned.
这汤明显太稀了，而且调味过重。
It's completely inedible.
完全不能吃。
Okay.
好的。
I do apologize for that.
我对此非常抱歉。
Can I bring you another soup or would you like to order something else?
我给您换一份汤，或者您想点别的吗？
Take this foie gras back as well.
把这个鹅肝也拿回去。
It's rubbery and completely overcooked.
它又硬又老，完全煮过头了。
And look at the portion size.
看看这分量。
How can you charge $25 for a sliver of duck liver?
一小片鸭肝怎么能收25美元？
Right away, sir.
马上，先生。
Honey, come on.
亲爱的，别这样。
The foie gras was fine.
鹅肝没问题。
Why are you making such a big deal?
你为什么这么大惊小怪？
Are you trying to get our meal comped again?
你是不是又想让我们这顿饭免单？
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
We're paying for this and I'm shelling out my hard earned bucks.
我们付钱吃饭，我花的是自己辛苦赚的钱。
I expect value for money.
我期望物有所值。
Here you are, sir.
给您，先生。
I hope it is all right now.
希望现在没问题了。
The chef has prepared it especially for you.
厨师特意为您准备的。
Yes, fine.
是的，还行。
Honey, are you all right?
亲爱的，你没事吧？
Well I guess that's one lesson.
嗯，我想这是个教训。
Hey, if you're in a restaurant, don't be too rude to the waiter.
嘿，如果你在餐厅，别对服务员太粗鲁。
You never know what's going to happen.
你永远不知道会发生什么。
The waiter and the cook, right?
服务员和厨师，对吧？
Yeah, you don't want to offend that kitchen staff.
是的，你不想得罪厨房员工。
All right.
好的。
So we'll talk about that a little bit later on but now I think we had some really interesting
我们稍后再谈这个，但现在我觉得我们学到了一些非常有趣的
vocabulary of how to describe food that is not well prepared and we can take a look at
描述食物做得不好的词汇，我们可以在“语言要点”中看看。
that now in Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Language Takeaway.
All right, so the guy in this dialogue, he ordered a mushroom soup and he complained
好的，对话里的那个人点了一份蘑菇汤，他抱怨说
that the mushroom soup was too runny.
蘑菇汤太稀了。
Okay, the soup is too runny.
好的，汤太稀了。
Runny.
稀的。
So he wanted a cream of mushroom so it should be a little bit thicker.
所以他点的是奶油蘑菇汤，应该浓稠一点。
Yep.
是的。
But in this case, it was runny.
但这里，它很稀。
So when something is runny, it's too liquid.
所以当东西很稀时，就是太液态了。
Too liquid.
太液态了。
And I think we can relate it to a runny nose, right?
我觉得我们可以联想到流鼻涕，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
Okay, so when liquid is coming out of your nose, a runny nose, in this case, the soup
好的，当液体从鼻子里流出来时，就是流鼻涕，这里汤是稀的。
is runny.
汤很稀。
Right.
对。
And another thing that he was complaining about, the food was over seasoned.
他抱怨的另一件事是食物调味过重。
Over seasoned.
调味过重。
The food is over seasoned.
食物调味过重。
Okay, so if the food is over seasoned.
好的，如果食物调味过重。
It's too salty.
就是太咸了。
So it's another way of saying it's too salty.
所以这是说太咸的另一种方式。
Yeah, it's kind of a fancy cooking term.
是的，这有点像高级烹饪术语。
Now can I say if there's too much pepper in the food, can I say it's over seasoned?
那如果食物里胡椒太多，我能说它调味过重吗？
Well, technically no.
嗯，严格来说不行。
When a cook says something is over seasoned, he's talking salt only.
当厨师说东西调味过重时，他只指盐。
Only salt.
只指盐。
So the cream of mushroom is very runny, it's over seasoned, and he said it's completely
所以奶油蘑菇汤很稀，调味过重，他说它完全
inedible.
不能吃。
Inedible.
It's inedible.
它不能吃。
Inedible.
不能吃。
Now, this word edible.
现在，这个词“可食用的”。
You can eat it.
你可以吃它。
So we have this prefix inedible.
所以我们有前缀“不可-”。
You cannot eat it.
你不能吃它。
This is not possible.
这不可能。
Yep.
是的。
And it doesn't mean that physically you can't eat it.
这并不意味着你身体上不能吃它。
It just means it's pretty disgusting.
只是说它很恶心。
Okay.
好的。
This food is inedible.
这食物不能吃。
And then he started to complain about the other dish and he said that it's rubbery.
然后他开始抱怨另一道菜，说它又硬又老。
Rubbery.
又硬又老。
The foie gras was rubbery.
鹅肝又硬又老。
All right.
好的。
So I think we noticed the word rubber.
我想我们注意到了“橡胶”这个词。
So obviously if a food is rubbery, it's too chewy.
所以显然如果食物又硬又老，就是太有嚼劲了。
It's like chewing on the bottom of your shoe, right?
就像嚼鞋底一样，对吧？
Okay, so it's too hard to chew or to swallow.
好的，所以太难嚼或难以下咽。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好的。
And apparently the food was rubbery because it's completely overcooked.
显然食物又硬又老是因为完全煮过头了。
Overcooked.
煮过头了。
All right.
好的。
We have overcooked.
我们有“煮过头”。
So when something is overcooked, I mean it's easy to understand that it's cooked too much.
所以当东西煮过头时，很容易理解是煮得太久了。
But it doesn't mean that it's burnt, right?
但这不意味着烧焦了，对吧？
No.
不。
So maybe you've ordered your steak to be rare, but it comes to you well done.
所以也许你点了三分熟的牛排，但上来的却是全熟的。
So it's not burnt, but it's cooked too much.
所以没烧焦，但煮得太久了。
So also I guess we can say like chicken.
所以我想我们也可以说鸡肉。
Sometimes if you overcook chicken, it comes out too dry.
有时如果你把鸡肉煮过头，它会变得太干。
Yep.
是的。
Right.
对。
So to overcook something.
所以是煮过头了。
And finally he was complaining about the size of the dish and he said, this is a sliver
最后他抱怨菜的分量，他说这是一小片鸭肝。
of duck liver.
一小片鸭肝。
Okay.
好的。
A sliver.
一小片。
All right.
好的。
Now this word sliver is like a slice, right?
现在这个词“一小片”就像一片，对吧？
A very small, tiny little slice.
非常小的一小片。
Okay.
好的。
So we can say, okay, I just want a sliver of bacon for breakfast.
所以我们可以说，好的，我早餐只想吃一小片培根。
All right.
好的。
Let's look at a few more examples of how we can use sliver.
让我们再看几个如何使用“一小片”的例子。
Example one.
例子一。
No, John's on a diet.
不，John在节食。
He'll just have a sliver of cake and no ice cream.
他只要一小块蛋糕，不要冰淇淋。
Example two.
例子二。
I'm really full, but it looks so delicious.
我真的很饱了，但它看起来太好吃了。
Can you just cut me a sliver?
你能只给我切一小块吗？
Example three.
例子三。
You call this sliver of beef on my plate a meal?
你管我盘子里这一小片牛肉叫一顿饭？
There's almost nothing here.
这里几乎什么都没有。
And those are all the words we had for language takeaway.
这些就是我们在“语言要点”里学到的所有词。
Now you have, so we've given you different adjectives of describing food that is not
现在你有了，我们给了你不同的形容词来描述做得不好的食物。
well prepared.
做得不好的食物。
So now let's move on to some other phrases that the customer used to complain in Fluency
现在让我们继续看顾客在“流利度构建”中用来抱怨的其他短语。
Builder.
流利度构建。
Fluency Builder.
Okay.
好的。
So before we get to the customer complaining language, I want to look at a phrase that
在我们看顾客抱怨的语言之前，我想先看一个
the waiter used to apologize.
服务员用来道歉的短语。
He said, I do apologize.
他说，我确实道歉。
I do apologize.
我确实道歉。
Now, why is this phrase so interesting?
为什么这个短语这么有趣？
Well, I mean, it's pretty easy to understand the meaning, but I want to look at why he
嗯，意思很容易理解，但我想看看为什么他
added this verb do.
加了动词“do”。
Well, he added the verb do to this phrase to make it seem a little bit stronger, to
嗯，他在这个短语里加了动词“do”来让它显得更强一些，
give a little more power to his apology.
给他的道歉增加一点力度。
Right.
对。
So if you have an affirmative phrase, like I apologize, it's good.
所以如果你有一个肯定短语，比如“我道歉”，这很好。
If you want to give it a little bit more emphasis, you can say, I do apologize.
如果你想给它多一点强调，你可以说“我确实道歉”。
Why don't we give an example?
我们为什么不举个例子？
So I might say this, Marco, I didn't know we had a party tonight.
所以我可能会这样说，Marco，我不知道我们今晚有派对。
And I might say, what?
我可能会说，什么？
I did tell you about it last week.
我上周确实告诉过你。
Right.
对。
So you're just giving a little bit more power to the statement that you told me.
所以你只是给“我告诉过你”这个陈述增加了一点力度。
So this do, did, does, becomes an auxiliary to make it more powerful, to give it more
所以这个“do”、“did”、“does”变成了一个助动词，让它更有力，给它更多
emphasis.
强调。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
And a neat little phrase, something you can use if you want to make your apologies sound
还有一个很简洁的短语，如果你想让你道歉的语气听起来
maybe a little bit stronger.
稍微更强烈一点，可以用它。
All right.
好的。
Now moving on to the next phrase, he was complaining about the food and it was terrible.
现在我们来看下一个短语，他在抱怨食物，说食物很糟糕。
And he said, I'm shelling out my hard earned bucks.
他说：“我花了我辛苦赚来的钱。”
Okay, let's break this one down into two sections.
好的，我们把这个短语分成两部分来讲解。
We'll start with shelling out.
我们先从“shelling out”开始。
All right.
好的。
So to shell out.
所以“to shell out”。
So when you shell out, you pay for something.
当你“shell out”时，你是在为某样东西付钱。
All right.
好的。
So this gives you the sensation that you are, that you don't really want to pay.
所以这给人一种感觉，就是你其实不太想付钱。
You're a bit unhappy about it.
你对此有点不高兴。
Right.
对。
So you want to shell out your money.
所以你是在“shell out your money”。
Why don't we listen to some examples to show us how we can use this phrase to shell out.
我们不如听一些例子，看看怎么用这个短语“to shell out”。
Example one.
例子一。
Great.
太好了。
It's my girlfriend's birthday this month.
这个月是我女朋友的生日。
So I'm going to have to shell out for a present.
所以我得花钱买个礼物。
Example two.
例子二。
I really want those shoes, but I can't really afford to shell out $400.
我真的很想要那双鞋，但我实在付不起400美元。
Example three.
例子三。
I can't believe it.
我真不敢相信。
Ella shelled out the 800 bucks for the tickets.
艾拉花了800美元买票。
I thought I would have to pay.
我还以为得我付钱呢。
All right.
好的。
So now that we understand shell out, let's move on to the second part of that sentence.
现在我们理解了“shell out”，接着看那句话的第二部分。
My hard earned bucks.
我辛苦赚来的钱。
Hard earned bucks.
辛苦赚来的钱。
My hard earned bucks.
我辛苦赚来的钱。
Okay.
好的。
So bucks are dollars, right?
所以“bucks”就是美元，对吧？
Dollars, only dollars, right?
美元，只是美元，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
Not pounds, not euros.
不是英镑，不是欧元。
But his hard earned bucks is money he had to work really hard for.
但“his hard earned bucks”是他必须非常努力工作才能赚到的钱。
So I can also say my hard earned money, right?
所以我也可以说“my hard earned money”，对吧？
Or my hard earned cash.
或者“my hard earned cash”。
Exactly.
没错。
Very good.
非常好。
So you worked hard to get it.
所以你努力工作才得到它。
All right.
好的。
So three great phrases that can be used when you're complaining in a restaurant.
所以这三个很棒的短语可以在餐厅抱怨时使用。
Why don't we hear them one last time in context by listening to the dialogue.
我们不如最后再听一遍对话，看看它们在语境中的用法。
Excuse me, waiter.
打扰一下，服务员。
Yes, sir.
是的，先生。
What can I do for you?
有什么可以为您效劳？
I've been sitting here for the past 20 minutes and no one has offered me a glass of water,
我在这里坐了20分钟，没人给我倒杯水，
brought any bread to the table, and our appetizers haven't been served yet.
也没人把面包端上桌，我们的开胃菜还没上。
You know, in this kind of establishment, I'd expect much better service.
你知道，在这种档次的餐厅，我期待更好的服务。
I'm sorry, sir.
对不起，先生。
I'll check on your order right away.
我马上去查一下您的订单。
Relax, honey.
放松点，亲爱的。
The place is busy tonight and I've heard the food is amazing.
今晚这里很忙，我听说食物很棒。
Anyway.
不管怎样。
Here you are, sir.
给您，先生。
The foie gras for the lady and a mushroom soup for you.
女士的鹅肝和您的蘑菇汤。
Waiter!
服务员！
I ordered a cream of mushroom soup with asparagus.
我点的是芦笋奶油蘑菇汤。
The soup is obviously too runny and it's over seasoned.
这汤明显太稀了，而且调味过重。
It's completely inedible.
完全没法吃。
Okay, I do apologize for that.
好的，我为此道歉。
Can I bring you another soup or would you like to order something else?
我给您换一份汤，或者您想点别的什么？
Take this foie gras back as well.
把这个鹅肝也拿回去。
It's rubbery and completely overcooked.
它又硬又老，完全煮过头了。
And look at the portion size.
看看这分量。
How can you charge $25 for a sliver of duck liver?
一小片鸭肝你怎么能收25美元？
Right away, sir.
马上来，先生。
Honey, come on.
亲爱的，别这样。
The foie gras was fine.
鹅肝没问题啊。
Why are you making such a big deal?
你为什么这么大惊小怪？
Are you trying to get our meal comped again?
你是不是又想让我们这顿饭免单？
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
We're paying for this and I'm shelling out my hard earned bucks.
我们付钱吃饭，我花的是我辛苦赚来的钱。
I expect value for money.
我要求物有所值。
Here you are, sir.
给您，先生。
I hope it is all right now.
希望现在没问题了。
The chef has prepared it especially for you.
厨师特意为您准备的。
Yes, fine.
是的，还行。
Honey, are you all right?
亲爱的，你没事吧？
So complaining at a restaurant and actually sending food back is not uncommon in the US.
所以在美国，在餐厅抱怨并把食物退回去并不少见。
Yeah, of course.
是的，当然。
If the food's bad, of course you're going to send it back.
如果食物不好，你当然会退回去。
But maybe in other cultures, I think people would be a little bit more reluctant to do
但也许在其他文化中，我觉得人们会更不愿意做
something like this.
这样的事情。
Yeah.
是的。
But hey, you know what's an interesting thing about the way Americans eat in restaurants
但嘿，你知道美国人去餐厅吃饭的一个有趣之处是
is sometimes at the end of the meal, if they haven't finished everything, they might ask
有时在用餐结束时，如果他们没吃完所有东西，可能会要
for a doggy bag.
一个“狗食袋”。
A doggy bag, yeah.
“狗食袋”，是的。
So what is that, a doggy bag?
那是什么，“狗食袋”？
Well, usually if you order a big meal or half your steak is left over on your plate, you
嗯，通常如果你点了一大份餐，或者半块牛排剩在盘子里，你
would ask for a doggy bag and they would bring you a little box or a bag and you would take
会要一个“狗食袋”，他们会给你一个小盒子或袋子，你
it to supposedly give it to your dog.
把它带回去，据说是给你狗吃的。
Right.
对。
So it's sort of like you tell the waiter, oh, the steak was so good, I couldn't finish
所以有点像你对服务员说，哦，牛排太好吃了，我没吃完，
it, can I take some home to my dog?
我能带点回家给我狗吗？
Right.
对。
So you would just ask, waiter, can I have a doggy bag?
所以你只需问，服务员，能给我一个“狗食袋”吗？
Right.
对。
But it's sort of like code for I'm going to eat this tomorrow for lunch.
但这有点像暗语，意思是明天午饭我要吃这个。
Exactly.
没错。
So people wouldn't really give it to their dog.
所以人们其实不会真的给狗吃。
You know, that steak wrapped up in a fancy sort of foil salon is going to be a pretty
你知道，那块牛排用漂亮的锡纸包起来，第二天
delicious the next day.
会非常美味。
Right.
对。
Yeah.
是的。
It's actually very common in the US, but in other countries, people will leave entire
这在美国其实很常见，但在其他国家，人们会把整盘
plates of food on the table.
食物留在桌上。
It would be totally impolite to ask the waiter to pack up the food for you.
让服务员帮你打包食物会完全不礼貌。
Exactly.
没错。
So a little bit of cultural differences, but we want to know what you think and how things
所以有点文化差异，但我们想知道你的看法，以及
are done maybe in your country with complaining or sending food back or even this whole doggy
在你的国家，抱怨、退食物，甚至整个“狗食袋”
bag situation.
的情况是怎么样的。
That's right.
没错。
Why don't you visit our website, EnglishPod.com and tell us about it.
为什么不去我们的网站 EnglishPod.com 告诉我们呢？
All right.
好的。
We'll be there to answer any questions or comments, but we got to go now.
我们会在那里回答任何问题或评论，但现在我们得走了。
So until then.
那么下次见。
Goodbye.
再见。
From Jeff and Charlie's view of what it's like to not have a dog.
来自杰夫和查理对没有狗是什么感觉的看法。